Guide to the Jess A. Shenson's Chinese in San Francisco: illustrations, 1870-1900 and n.d.
Department of Special Collections
Shenson, A. Jess, collector. Chinese in San Francisco: illustrations,
1870-1900 and n.d.
M1120
Shenson, A. Jess, collector.
4 linear ft. (22 matted prints of 33 illustrations)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Primarily wood engravings from Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, but also includes one process print, 2 half tone prints, and a colored heliogravure.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Ira & B. Gerald Cantor Center for Visual Arts, Stanford University, 2000. Previously given to the Cantor Center by collector, Dr. A. Jess Shenson.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Primarily wood engravings from Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, but also includes one process print, 2 half tone prints, and a colored heliogravure.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Baker, H.; Bode, William Walter.; Davis, G.A.; Frenzeny, Paul.; Langguth, T.; Ogden, H.; Taber, I. West.; Tavernier, Jules.; Yeager, Walter.; Chinese--California--San Francisco.; Chinatown (San Francisco, Calif.); Wood-engraving.; Shenson, A. Jess, collector.
Collection Contents
- The Coming Man-Scene in the Hallway of a House in the Chinese Quarter; and The Coming Man-Scene in the Joss House in the Chinese Quarter. Both wood engravings in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper1870 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Altar in a Chinese Joss House, San Francisco. Wood engraving in Harper's Weekly1871 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Altar in the Chinese Joss-House. Wood engraving in Harper's Weekly1871 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A Holiday in Chinatown. Wood engraving in Harper's Weekly1880 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- California-Chinese Mission School at the Methodist Chapel, Jackson Street. Wood engraving in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper1876 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- California-Interior of a Chinese Joss House. Wood engraving from a photograph by I.W. Taber in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper1888 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A haunt of the Highbinders in Chinatown. Wood engraving in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Searching Chinese Immigrants for Opium. Wood engraving from a sketch by W.W. Bode in Harper's Weekly1882 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Chinese Merchants' Exchange. Wood engraving drawn by Paul Frenzeny, from a sketch by W.W. Bode, in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Among the Chinese on the Pacific Coast. Process print drawn by Frederick T. Langguth in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 2, Folder 10)
- A Street in Chinatown. From a picture by Miss G.A. Davis, wood engraving in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper1891 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Chinese Immigrants at the San Francisco Custom House. Wood engravng by Paul Frenzeny in Harper's Weekly1877 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Burning the Prayers-Chinese Superstitions. Wood engraving by Paul Frenzeny in Harper's Weekly1873 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- The Chinese in San Francisco: 5 scenes. Wood engravings and one half tone print in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Scene in a Chinese Opium Palace. Wood engraving drawn by Paul Frenzeny in Harper's Weekly1880 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Chinese Fisherman in San Francisco Bay. Wood engraving drawn by Paul Frenzeny and Jules Tavernier in Harper's Weekly1875 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- A cChinese Burial in Lone Mountain Cemetery. Wood engraving drawn by Paul Frenzeny in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 3, Folder 17)
- The Chinaman's Paradise; a Favorite Haunt of Opium Smokers on Kearney Street. Wood engraving by H. Baker from sketches by H. Ogden and Walter Yeager in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper1878 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Theatrical Performances in China-Town. Wood engraving drawn by Paul Frenzeny in Harper's Weeklynd (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Sketches in China Town: 6 wood engravings drawn by Paul Frenzeny and Jules Tavernier, hand colored in Harper's Weekly1875 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- The Bubonic Plague: Chinamen, Confined within the Chinese Quarter, Cooking their meals. Half tone print in Harper's Weeklyc. 1900 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Motiv aus dem Chinesenviertel. Colored heliogravure signed Rud. Crenao1883 (Box 4, Folder 22)